A Finding Aid to the Henri Gallery Records, circa early 1900s, 1940-1996, bulk 1957-1995, in the Archives of American Art AAA.henrgall
Archives of American Art
- Alphabetical Files, 1947-1996; Series 2; 50.1 Linear feet Boxes 3-52, 55-57, OV 58
  - Name Files, 1947-1996; 2.1
    - Oversized Envelope, Ken Adams, 1988-1989 (Box 56, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 4, Folder 2
    - Oversized Illustrated Envelope, John Gerald Balsley, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      Oversized material from Box 7, Folder 12
    - Oversized Notated Envelope, Joyce Cutler-Shaw, circa 1975 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      Oversized material from Box 14, Folder 30
    - Oversized Clipping, Joan Danzinger, 1970 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      Oversized material from Box 14, Folder 39
    - Oversized Exhibition Catalog, Predrag (Yugo) Djordjevic, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      Oversized material from Box 16, Folder 8
    - Oversized Sketch, Ronald Grow, 1970 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      Oversized material from Box 21, Folder 19
    - Oversized Illustrated Correspondence, Manfred Hammes, 1989 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      Oversized material from Box 22, Folder 15
    - Oversized Envelope, Bill Jackson, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 6)
      Oversized material from Box 26, Folder 5
    - Oversized Photographs, Patricia Lasch, 1970s (Box 56, Folder 7)
      Oversized material from Box 30, Folder 5
    - Oversized Album Pages, Ardele Lister, circa 1977 (Box 56, Folder 7)
      Oversized material from Box 30, Folder 32
    - Oversized Artwork, Michael Bigger [Machine Tools], 1980 (Box 56, Folder 8)
      Oversized material from Box 31, Folder 3
    - Oversized Scrapbook Pages, Alfonse Pagano?, circa 1989 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Oversized material from Box 36, Folder 8
    - Oversized Artwork, Jerome Rettich, circa 1966-1969 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 38, Folder 16
    - Oversized Photograph, Italo Scanga, undated (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Oversized material from Box 40, Folder 8
    - Oversized Poster, Schwake, circa 1957-1967 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Oversized material from Box 41, Folder 12
    - Oversized Photograph, Lawson Smith, undated (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Oversized material from Box 43, Folder 5
    - Oversized Drawings, Richard Thompson, circa 1990 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Oversized material from Box 45, Folder 48
    - Oversized Photographs, Rosemary Wright, circa 1973-1974 (Box 57, Folder 6)
      Oversized material from Box 50, Folder 21
    - Oversized Drawing (Ink), John Ferguson, circa 1972-1980 (Box OV 58)
      Oversized material from Box 18, Folder 10
    - Oversized Poster, Chris Hayman, 1970 (Box OV 58)
      Oversized material from Box 23, Folder 5
  - Subject Files, circa 1948-1996; 2.2
    Subject Files cover a range of art- and business-related topics from art coalitions and various genres of art, to mailing lists, lists of paintings sold, price lists, and tax information. Materials are comprised of brochures, exhibition announcements, lists, newspaper clippings, notes, and other miscellaneous materials. Also found are records related to the Not New Shop, including some notes written by Henri and a manuscript about the early years of the shop written by Florie King.
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Absolut Henri, Reviews Etc., 1963; 1991-1992 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - African Art, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Agents for Artists and Dealers, circa 1967-1968 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - American Indian, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Applications for Positions and Artists, 1963 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Art Law, 1995 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Art Martyrs - Chris Burden, Vito Acconci, Etc., 1976 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - "The Art Nobody Knows," Jed Perl, 1991-1992 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Art Taxes Information, 1968-1980 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Artists' Biographies, circa 1969-1971 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Autographs Including DeChirico [empty folder], circa 1957-1996 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Bay Area Artists, 1990 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Boston, 1990 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Coalitions, 1969-1970 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Computer Art, 1989-1991 (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Conceptual Art, 1970s (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Conservators, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Erotica, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - Exhibition Review, Museum of Modern Art, circa 1992 (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - Fantasy Furniture, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Galleries, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - George Washington Exhibition (1966), 1962-1966; 1975-1977 (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - Grants, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Henri Gallery Artists, circa 1970s-1996 (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Henri Gallery Sign Layout, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 27)
      Oversized material housed in Box 57, Folder 7
    - Lists of Artists' Files, circa 1960s-1996 (Box 52, Folder 28)
    - Mailing Lists, 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - Manuscript, Dress Shop Play by Florie King, circa 1949-1957 (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - Museum Directors/Dealers/Curators, circa 1990 (Box 52, Folder 31)
    - Notes by Henri, circa 1987 (Box 52, Folder 32)
    - Notes by Henri, Regarding Not New Consignment Shop, circa 1948-1957 (Box 52, Folder 33)
    - Paintings in Private Collections, 1961-1963 (Box 52, Folder 34)
    - Paintings Sold, 1962-1964 (Box 52, Folder 35)
    - Petition to Save Henri Gallery, circa 1966-1967 (Box 52, Folder 36)
    - Photography, 1975-1979 (Box 52, Folder 37)
    - Price Lists, circa 1960s-1984 (Box 52, Folder 38)
    - Realism, 1970-1979 (Box 52, Folder 39)
    - Receipts Paid and Unpaid, 1970-1971 (Box 52, Folder 40)
    - Resales, 1980s-1991 (Box 52, Folder 41)
    - Restoration, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 42)
    - Returned Artwork Receipts, 1971-1974 (Box 52, Folder 43)
    - Sculpture, 1989-1991 (Box 52, Folder 44)
    - Venice Biennale 1966, 1966-1969 (Box 52, Folder 45)
    - Washington D.C. Artists and Critics Opinions, circa 1958-1964 (Box 52, Folder 46)
    - Oversized Sign Layout, Henri Gallery Sign Layout, 1984 (Box 57, Folder 7)
      Oversized material from Box 52, Folder 27
    - Oversized Poster, Art Workers Coalition, circa 1969-1970 (Box OV 58)
      Oversized material from Box 52, Folder 16
- Printed Materials, circa early 1900s; 1940-1995; Series 3; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 52-53, 57, OVs 59-61
  The bulk of the materials found in this series are newspaper clippings regarding artists, exhibitions, and Henri Gallery. There are also 114 posters from Henri Gallery exhibitions and other galleries' exhibitions of artists in which the Henri Gallery represented. Also found is an Excelsior 6 cent Classics booklet published by D.H. Knowlton & Co. dating from the early 1900s. Additional printed materials are found throughout the Alphabetical Files.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Booklet, "The Man Without a Country," by Edward Everett Hale, circa early 1900s (Box 52, Folder 47)
  - Clippings, 1948-1989 (Box 52, Folder 48-54)
  - Clippings, 1987-1989 (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
  - Clippings, Auctions, 1989-1992 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, D.C. Galleries, 1991 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, Henri Gallery, 1970-1975 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    Oversized material housed in Box 57, Folder 8
  - Clippings, Jasper Johns and Others, 1988; 1983 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, Robert Mapplethorpe, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous, 1983-1989 (Box 53, Folder 8-9)
  - Clippings, Not New Shop, 1949 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, Reviews/Auctions, 1991-1995 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, Reviews and Collectors, 1965-1983 (Box 53, Folder 12-13)
  - Clippings, Selective Service, 1940 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, Some Collectors, 1987-1988 (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, V.C.U. and Other [MFA Programs], 1994 (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, Andy Warhol [and Others], 1980; 1988 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Clippings, 1960s-1980 (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Gallery Fliers, 1955-circa 1967 (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - Posters, Exhibitions, 1959-1979 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    Oversized material housed in OVs 59-61
  - Oversized Clippings, Henri Gallery, 1972 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    Oversized material from Box 53, Folder 5
  - Oversized Exhibition Posters, 1959-1979 (Box OV 59)
    Oversized material from Box 53, Folder 20
  - Oversized Exhibition Posters, circa 1962-1976 (Box OV 60)
  - Oversized Exhibition Posters, circa 1961-1977 (Box OV 61)
- Artwork, 1952-circa 1996; Series 4; 5 Folders Boxes 53, 57
  This series is comprised of loose drawings and sketches, many of Henri. Folders are arranged alphabetically by medium of artwork.
  - Drawings by Artists, Gifts to Henri [Cards], circa 1980s-1996 (Box 53, Folder 21)
  - Henri Portrait [John Zambelis?], circa 1960s (Box 53, Folder 22)
  - Painting by Helen E., 1952 (Box 53, Folder 23)
  - Sketches, 1960s-1970s (Box 53, Folder 24)
  - Watercolor for Helen, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 53, Folder 25)
    Oversized material housed in Box 57, Folder 9
  - Oversized Watercolor for Helen, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 57, Folder 9)
    Oversized material from Box 53, Folder 25
- Photographic Materials, 1940s-1981; Series 5; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 53-54, 57
  Photographic Materials contains black and white photographs, scattered color photographs, snapshots, and slides of artwork, exhibitions, Henri, the galleries spaces, and the Not New shop. Most photographs are undated.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject. Photographic materials of unidentified artwork are filed at the end of the series.
  - Henri Ehrsam, 1940s-1960s (Box 53, Folder 26)
  - Exhibition Openings, 1959-1970s (Box 53, Folder 27)
  - Exhibitions and People, 1973, March (Box 53, Folder 28)
  - Exteriors of Henri Galleries, 1948-circa 1970s (Box 53, Folder 29)
  - Gallery Installations, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 53, Folder 30)
  - Henri Gallery Slides and Gallery History, 1961-1973 (Box 53, Folder 31)
  - Not New Consignment Shop and Henri Gallery, Alexandria, circa 1948-1967 (Box 53, Folder 32-33)
    Oversized material housed in Box 57, Folder 10
  - Unidentified Artwork, Photographs, circa 1960-1981 (Box 53, Folder 34)
  - Unidentified Artwork, Photographs, circa 1960-1981 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified Artwork, Slides, circa 1960s-1981 (Box 54, Folder 2-3)
  - Oversized Photographs, Not New Consignment Shop and Henri Gallery, Alexandria, circa 1948-1967 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    Oversized material from Box 53, Folder 33